<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: frugal | Ross Lancaster]]></title>
  <link href="http://ToastyMallows.github.io/blog/categories/frugal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ToastyMallows.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-08-24T00:29:30-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://ToastyMallows.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ross Lancaster]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go to your local Estate Sales]]></title>
    <link href="http://ToastyMallows.github.io/go-to-your-local-estate-sales/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-04T23:32:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ToastyMallows.github.io/go-to-your-local-estate-sales</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you are anything like the people I’ve met in my life thus far, you’ve never been to an estate sale.  Do you collect things?  Do you want to furnish your new house?  Have you always wondered what the inside of your neighbors house looked like?  Do you just like old stuff?  If you answered yes to any of these questions, you would love going to the estate sales in your town.<!--more--></p>

<p>Estate sales are such a great place to get stuff for cheap.  And sometimes, even cheaper than thrift stores or garage sales.  </p>

<p>Consider this; You’re hired to sell all of the contents of someones home after they have recently passed away or decided to move.  What do you do?  You don’t want to price things too expensive or else people will never buy them, and you don’t want to under sell something that you could have gotten double on.  Also, houses have <em>a lot</em> of things in them, especially if they’ve been lived in for 30-40 years.  With this in mind, you’ll probably price some items higher and expect to come down, yet on others you’ll mark them low just to get them out of the door.  Others still, you’ll just have people come up and ask what you’ll take for it at the cash register during the sale.</p>

<p>This is exactly the situation that most estate sale runners are faced with, how much product to be left over at the end of the weekend.  The leftover items will most likely be liquidated (at a loss most likely, as everything will be sold in bulk to the highest bidder), or in some cases, donated to thrift stores (old books, vhs tapes, etc.)  So they want to sell you the items when you’re there.</p>

<p>This is where you come in.  Compile a list of things that you would want to have (in my case: keychains, electronics, games, tchotchkes, weird or unique items, quick ebay sells), then peruse your local newspaper/Craigslist/<a href="http://www.estatesales.net/">estatesales.net</a> for the estate sales in your town that week.  Most likely there will be 3 or 4 going on that week, sometimes very close to your house.</p>

<p>Then, plan to visit them!  When looking around for stuff you want or need, remember that the people selling these items are trying to get items out the door.  They understand that you’re looking for a deal, and in most cases, will happily bargin with you to get the best price for both of you.  The best deals are when both parties feel that they’re winning with the price that’s being negotiated.  When in doubt, use your common sense.  Ask questions to yourself like:  Is this worth it for the price?  Will I use this?  Could I get one brand new for less or the same price?  This questions and similar ones will guide you through most negotiations.</p>

<p>Some estate sales are tough.  Most things you see will be over priced, and you’ll start getting freaked out, but <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phrases_from_The_Hitchhiker's_Guide_to_the_Galaxy#Don.27t_Panic">don’t panic</a>!  Sometimes this is just to weed out the people who aren’t serious buyers, other times, they just don’t know how to price things.  Go through the sale like normal, pick up things that you like and start to bargin with the sale runners.  If they aren’t budging, just calmly put the items down and walk away.  Most of the time, it’s not worth the argument over prices.  </p>

<p>This is perhaps the worst part about estate sales, finding something cool and the sellers just aren’t coming down on the price (even for trival things, kitchen ware, old books).  You’ll have to make a judgement call for yourself if you ever get into this situation, pay the money or walk away?  Sometimes when the prices are too outrageous, I just leave and go to the next sale. You may be able to come back later in the week at the end of the sale to get the same thing for cheaper when the sellers are getting desperate sell things, but, you run the risk of someone else buying your item.  </p>

<p>It always kills me when I see sellers who are on the last day of their sale and have tons of things left to sell because they don’t want to budge on any price.  What they don’t understand is that if you’re selling something secondhand, <em>you’re never going to sell it at the original price, even if it’s mint condition</em>.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup></p>

<p>Something else I’ve seen people do is always be connected on the phone with someone.  On the other end of the line is a friend or family member that is just searching Google/Ebay/Craigslist for the price of everything their friend is looking at.  Most of the time, these people are serious buyers and are willing to pay sticker price for something they know that they can turn around easily for a profit.  These people usually own a second hand store and/or care way too much about their Ebay rating.</p>

<p>I guarantee if you go out and use your best judgement you’ll walk away with some items that you wanted for much less than you were willing to pay for.  In the end, even if you didn’t get anything, it was probably fun just to go out and see everything that was for sale.  </p>

<p>Be assured that I’ll be posting about estate sales and garage sales more in the future, as I’ve been crusing them casually for 5+ years and found some awesome deals along the way.</p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>The only exception to this is if the item is rare or collectable, for example anything signed by a celebrity, Tiffany &amp; Co. items, certain types of jewlery and one-of-a-kind items like street signs, paintings by certain artists, etc.  These are rare finds and usually the seller is already aware of the items worth, thus the reason for the markup.<a href="#fnref:1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frugal Roadtrip Advice]]></title>
    <link href="http://ToastyMallows.github.io/frugal-roadtrip-advice/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-02T21:14:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ToastyMallows.github.io/frugal-roadtrip-advice</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I tend to be very frugal.  So when my girlfriend and I decided to go on a roadtrip after we were done with school I decided that we would do it as cheaply as possible.<!--more--></p>

<p>One of our biggest hangups early on was the fact that we didn’t want to spend $70/night or more on a hotel or B&amp;B.  I saw on <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/frugal">/r/frugal</a> that some WalMarts would let you sleep in your car in their parking lots overnight, either with a RV or just a regular car.</p>

<p>After reading many reviews and feedback from people who have done this, it’s very hit or miss.  I read on <a href="http://themorningfresh.com/2012/06/29/a-guide-to-car-camping-in-walmart-parking-lots/">this guide</a> to WalMart parking lot camping that the founder of WalMart has been vocal about his stores providing a safe spot for people on the road to stay overnight.  Even with this, some WalMarts definitely <strong>do not</strong> let you sleep overnight in their parking lots.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup></p>

<p>So I got to thinking, where could you park overnight and definitely <strong>not</strong> be bugged.  Then it hit me, hotel parking lots!  This provides a nice place to sleep during the night, lots are usually filled with many cars so you’ll just blend in.  In the morning, go in and use the restroom, if it’s a nice hotel get a free cup of coffee and be on your way!  I think it would be better if your car had some tinted windows in the back, at least for a small bit of privacy.  In addition, you could put a foldable sunshade in the front windsheild for even more privacy.</p>

<p>I imagine that we’ll be using this a lot on our roadtrip.  We plan on leaving the week of August 19th, 2013.  During the roadtrip and some more before I’ll be sure to share any plans we have of saving some money and seeing the country!</p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p><a href="http://www.allstays.com/apps/walmart.htm">This app might be helpful to some people</a><a href="#fnref:1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
