<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: roadtrip | Ross Lancaster]]></title>
  <link href="http://toastymallows.github.io/blog/categories/roadtrip/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://toastymallows.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-12T01:05:04-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://toastymallows.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ross Lancaster]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frugal Roadtrip Advice]]></title>
    <link href="http://toastymallows.github.io/frugal-roadtrip-advice/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-02T21:14:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://toastymallows.github.io/frugal-roadtrip-advice</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I tend to be very frugal.  So when my girlfriend and I decided to go on a roadtrip after we were done with school I decided that we would do it as cheaply as possible.<!--more--></p>

<p>One of our biggest hangups early on was the fact that we didn&rsquo;t want to spend $70/night or more on a hotel or B&amp;B.  I saw on <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/frugal">/r/frugal</a> that some WalMarts would let you sleep in your car in their parking lots overnight, either with a RV or just a regular car.</p>

<p>After reading many reviews and feedback from people who have done this, it&rsquo;s very hit or miss.  I read on <a href="http://themorningfresh.com/2012/06/29/a-guide-to-car-camping-in-walmart-parking-lots/">this guide</a> to WalMart parking lot camping that the founder of WalMart has been vocal about his stores providing a safe spot for people on the road to stay overnight.  Even with this, some WalMarts definitely <strong>do not</strong> let you sleep overnight in their parking lots.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup></p>

<p>So I got to thinking, where could you park overnight and definitely <strong>not</strong> be bugged.  Then it hit me, hotel parking lots!  This provides a nice place to sleep during the night, lots are usually filled with many cars so you&rsquo;ll just blend in.  In the morning, go in and use the restroom, if it&rsquo;s a nice hotel get a free cup of coffee and be on your way!  I think it would be better if your car had some tinted windows in the back, at least for a small bit of privacy.  In addition, you could put a foldable sunshade in the front windsheild for even more privacy.</p>

<p>I imagine that we&rsquo;ll be using this a lot on our roadtrip.  We plan on leaving the week of August 19th, 2013.  During the roadtrip and some more before I&rsquo;ll be sure to share any plans we have of saving some money and seeing the country!</p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p><a href="http://www.allstays.com/apps/walmart.htm">This app might be helpful to some people</a><a href="#fnref:1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
