<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: family | Ross Lancaster]]></title>
  <link href="http://toastymallows.github.io/blog/categories/family/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://toastymallows.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-12T01:09:37-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://toastymallows.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ross Lancaster]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Family Reunions]]></title>
    <link href="http://toastymallows.github.io/family-reunions/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-09T21:11:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://toastymallows.github.io/family-reunions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This year will be my 22<sup>nd</sup> family reunion.  That&rsquo;s one for every year I&rsquo;ve been alive.  Family reunions are a like second nature to me.  I&rsquo;ve asked a lot of my friends if they have family reunions, most of them said no.  Some commented that family was too far away to have a reunion every year, but I think it&rsquo;s important enough to make the trek.</p>

<p>One of my great aunt&rsquo;s husband comes to our family reunion every year.  He has a large family tree that he manages and he brings it every year to write down updates. Deaths, births, marriages and divorces all get recorded.  It&rsquo;s nice to have that solid of a family history written down and able to be referenced.  It gives me a great idea of where I come from and my place in the world.  Hopefully one day I can take over updating the tree.</p>

<p>Recently, my family found out that one of our ancestors lied about their nationality on an immigration form in the early 1900s.<!--more-->  Someone had visited <a href="http://Ancestry.com">Ancestry.com</a> and brought the printed out proof that a couple who was once thought to be 100% German, was now 50% German and 50% Polish.  To me this didn&rsquo;t make a difference, but for some (older) family members, it was a complete shock.</p>

<p>Times have changed I guess.  Nationality for me really isn&rsquo;t that important.  Eventually everything is going to be so mixed together that it would be pointless to care, but it&rsquo;s fun to learn where you&rsquo;re from.  For some family members that grew up in the 1930s, this was a game changer.  Imagine that you think your whole life that you&rsquo;re a certain percentage German (Maybe %50 or even %100), and now you&rsquo;re Polish as well.  If you didn&rsquo;t know, <a href="http://www.spiegel.de/international/europe/the-unloved-neighbors-a-history-of-hostility-between-poland-and-germany-a-489510.html">German-Polish relations aren&rsquo;t exactly rock solid</a>.  Just recently in 2005, the late Polish President Lech Kaczynski, when asked about his countries threats, responded by saying &ldquo;Threats? Those are our neighbors &ndash; Russia and Germany.&rdquo;</p>

<p>But, family being family, everything eventually evened out.  The main reason I like going is to just see everyone that I would normally never see, or only see for happy/sad events (Christmas/Funerals respectively).  It&rsquo;s nice to get an update on how life is moving along for everyone.  A chance to relax, play some bocce ball, and enjoy some cheesy potatoes.</p>

<p>Do you have a family reunion?  If not, you should consider hosting one soon!  Since family is more spread out now-a-days, we always invite people that can&rsquo;t make it to send a message (snailmail/email) so that it can be read out during our annual meeting (to decide on dues for next year, location, time, family updates).  We have some casual guessing games, eat some food and enjoy eachothers company.  Who knows, maybe yours will still be going after 51 years like ours has!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
