<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: error codes | Ross Lancaster]]></title>
  <link href="http://ToastyMallows.github.io/blog/categories/error-codes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ToastyMallows.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-08-24T00:29:30-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://ToastyMallows.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ross Lancaster]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[P0606 OBD-II code on a 2008 Toyota Camry]]></title>
    <link href="http://ToastyMallows.github.io/p0606-obd-ii-code-on-a-2008-toyota-camry/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-15T21:25:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ToastyMallows.github.io/p0606-obd-ii-code-on-a-2008-toyota-camry</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A couple of days ago I had some lights come up on the dash of my 2008 Toyota Camry.  The slip indicator, VSC and Check Engine lights were on.  First I did a quick check of my gas cap to see if it was sealed completely, because this is one of the common reasons why a check engine light would be on.
<!-- more -->
After checking that, I went to my local AutoZone to get the code read.  The code that came up was P0606: PCM/ECM Processor Fault<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>.  The guy that helped me read my code seemed very confused as to why this code was coming up on such a new model of car.  He asked if I recently installed any new stereo systems or speakers, to which I said no.</p>

<p>Knowingly or not, he reset the code on my car.  Upon returning home to research this code further I couldn’t find anything that specific to my model car.  Luckily I found <a href="http://www.xr-underground.com/forum/archive/index.php/t-1692.html">this blog post</a> from a couple Google searches.  User <em>blackx-runner</em> described the same problem that I was having, although I didn’t notice my car reacting any different when on the road.  Recently we’ve had a lot of rain here and he said that he noticed his truck getting the error after a carwash or heavy rain.  I’ve had my car outside a lot so I think my issue may be related to this.</p>

<p>I’ll keep this blog post updated with any problems I have with this problem, but for now a simple reset seems to have fixed it.</p>

<p><strong>Update 16 Oct. 2013</strong> - Still haven’t had the problem come back.  Looks like it was just a fluke.</p>

<p><strong>Update 23 Dec. 2013</strong> - Just had the error code happen again. It rained for about 2 days straight in Cleveland, I think that’s what caused it, though I can’t be sure. But this time it came with a bonus error code, P0138.  </p>

<p>Found a couple resources online, <a href="http://ww2.justanswer.com/uploads/snd27613/2008-10-22_002248_p0171.pdf">here</a> and <a href="http://www.toyotanation.com/forum/104-5th-6th-generation-2002-2006-2007-2011/337271-07-camry-v6-p0138-o2-sensor.html">here</a>.  According to the first link, the official Toyota PDF from 2008, it’s an issue that is covered under warrenty for 36 months or 36,000 miles, which I’m over both.</p>

<p>The second link, the ToyotaNation.com forum, user <em>yukon700</em> has the same problem as me, only his car is a 2007 Camry.  He says:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>After researching and talking to a friend he said I should just go to autozone and replace the O2 sensor which failed due to high voltage which is behind the catalytic converter and see if that works. Toyota warns that I need to replace everything and by just replacing the one sensor it will fry again and be a waste.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I’m going to take it to my mechanic and see what he says about all of this.</p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p><a href="http://www.obd-codes.com/p0606">http://www.obd-codes.com/p0606</a><a href="#fnref:1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
