<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: megaphone | Ross Lancaster]]></title>
  <link href="http://ToastyMallows.github.io/blog/categories/megaphone/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ToastyMallows.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-08-24T00:29:30-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://ToastyMallows.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ross Lancaster]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Buy a Megaphone]]></title>
    <link href="http://ToastyMallows.github.io/buy-a-megaphone/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-05T23:36:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ToastyMallows.github.io/buy-a-megaphone</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Going along with my previous post about Estate Sales, one of my best purchases was at one.  Buying a heavy-duty, vintage Megaphone.  I found it in the basement of someones house just waiting for me to purchase it, and I got it for $30.</p>

<p>At the time it seemed like a sizeable chunk of change to be throwing at something which would certainly be a novelty item or purely for entertainment, but it has come in handy a lot.</p>

<p>There are tons of times in your life where owning a Megaphone can help.  Throwing a big party?  Need to organize a rally of any sort?  Has someone asked you to help them at an organization or event?  Chances are you’ll need a megaphone to grab everyones attention.  There have been times where people have literally said to me “Man, I wish I had a megaphone for this”, to which I respond that I do, indeed, have one readily available.</p>

<p>Is it used a lot for fun?  Sure.  My megaphone, in addition to projecting my voice very loudly, comes with some built in sounds (tons of siren noises from the US and UK), and is great for scaring the shit out of people.</p>

<p>All in all, if you ever have the chance to buy one, do it!  It will greatly improve your life.  Go for broke and get one that runs off of a lantern 6-volt battery and a microphone attached to a coiled cable.  Pretty soon you’ll be renting it out to your friends.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
